Register of the Curt Max Prüfer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Curt Max Prüfer papers
1914-1954
87035
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Diaries, memoirs, report, and clippings relating to German military liaison with Turkish military operations during World War I, German foreign policy during the interwar period (especially in Ethiopia), and German foreign policy during World War II (especially in Brazil).
Prüfer, Curt Max, b. 1881.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1987.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Material
Prüfer, C. M., McKale, D. M., Melton, J. M., & Mazal Holocaust Collection. (1988). Rewriting history: The original and revised World War II diaries of Curt Prüfer, Nazi diplomat. Kent, Ohio: Kent State University Press.
Biographical Note
German diplomat; director of personnel, Auswärtiges Amt, 1936-1939; ambassador to Brazil, 1939-1942. Following retirement from government, Prüfer emmigrated to Switzerland.
Scope and Content of Collection
Diaries, memoirs, report, and clippings relating to German military liaison with Turkish military operations during World War I, German foreign policy during the interwar period (especially in Ethiopia), and German foreign policy during World War II (especially in Brazil).
Germany. Auswärtiges Amt.; Brazil--Foreign relations--Germany.; Diplomats--Germany.; Ethiopia--Foreign relations--Germany.; Germany--Foreign relations--Brazil.; Germany--Foreign relations--Ethiopia.; Germany--Foreign relations.; National socialism.; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--Turkey.; World War, 1914-1918--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.
- Biographical File, 1919-1950
  - Autobiography, handwritten and typescript drafts, circa 1940-1950 (Box-folder 1: 1-3)
  - General autobiographical writings, 1919, undated (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Newspaper clippings about Curt Max Prüfer, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- Diaries, 1914-1954
  - 1914-1918 (Box-folder 1: 6-8)
  - 1920 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - 1930 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - 1941 January 1 - December 31 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - 1942 October 18 - 1943 September 7 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - 1942 November 11 - 1944 January 7 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - 1944 January 10 - September 6 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - 1944 July - 1945 November 30 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - 1944 September 7 - 1946 April 21 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - 1946 March 13 - 1951 February 2 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - 1946 April 22 - 1949 April 12 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - 1949 April 13 - 1954 October 20 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - 1951 February 24 - May 27 (Box-folder 2: 8)